[{"question":"What is the definition of food?","answers":["A substance consumed to provide energy for the body","Any substance consumed to satisfy hunger","A substance made up of essential nutrients","Any substance consumed to provide nutritional support for the body"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Any substance consumed to provide nutritional support for the body"]},{"question":"What are macronutrients?","answers":["Nutrients that provide the necessary cofactors for metabolism","Nutrients that are necessary in large amounts for survival","Nutrients that help in the absorption of other nutrients","Nutrients that provide the bulk energy for an organism's metabolic system"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Nutrients that provide the bulk energy for an organism's metabolic system"]},{"question":"What is the composition of carbohydrates?","answers":["Carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen","Carbon, hydrogen, nitrogen, and sometimes phosphorus","Carbon, hydrogen, oxygen, and sometimes nitrogen and sulfur","Carbon, nitrogen, sulfur, and phosphorus"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen"]},{"question":"Which of the following is not a type of carbohydrate?","answers":["Glucose","Maltose","Sucrose","Cellulose"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Glucose"]},{"question":"What is the function of carbohydrates?","answers":["Maintain body temperature","Act as a lubricant in the body","Provide energy required for daily activities","Help in tissue repair"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Provide energy required for daily activities"]},{"question":"What is protein composed of?","answers":["Carbon, hydrogen, oxygen, and sometimes nitrogen","Carbon, nitrogen, sulfur, and phosphorus","Carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen","Carbohydrate, hydrogen, oxygen, nitrogen, and sometimes phosphorus and sulfur"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Carbohydrate, hydrogen, oxygen, nitrogen, and sometimes phosphorus and sulfur"]},{"question":"Which of the following is not a source of protein?","answers":["Fish","Beans","Garri","Egg"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Garri"]},{"question":"What is the importance of protein?","answers":["Used for growth, repair of tissues, reproduction, production of enzymes, and tissues and cells formation","Act as a lubricant in the body","Provide energy for daily activities","Maintain body temperature"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Used for growth, repair of tissues, reproduction, production of enzymes, and tissues and cells formation"]},{"question":"What is the composition of fats and oils?","answers":["Carbon, hydrogen, and little oxygen","Carbon, nitrogen, sulfur, and phosphorus","Carbon, hydrogen, nitrogen, and sometimes phosphorus","Carbon, hydrogen, oxygen, and sometimes nitrogen and sulfur"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Carbon, hydrogen, and little oxygen"]},{"question":"Which of the following is not a source of fats and oils?","answers":["Fish","Groundnut","Meat","Palm oil"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Meat"]},{"question":"What is the significance of fats and oils?","answers":["Act as a lubricant in the body","Provide more energy, supply essential fatty acids, provide fat-soluble vitamins, and help maintain body temperature","Aid in tissue repair","Act as a building block for body parts"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Provide more energy, supply essential fatty acids, provide fat-soluble vitamins, and help maintain body temperature"]},{"question":"What are mineral salts?","answers":["Nutrients required for metabolic activities, usually taken in minute quantities through food","Nutrients that help in the absorption of other nutrients","Nutrients that provide energy for daily activities","Nutrients that are necessary in large amounts for survival"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Nutrients required for metabolic activities, usually taken in minute quantities through food"]},{"question":"Which of the following is a source of calcium?","answers":["Fish","Beans","Groundnut","Milk"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Milk"]},{"question":"What is the function of calcium?","answers":["Bone and teeth formation, blood clotting, and normal functioning of the heart, nervous system, and muscles","For strong development of bones and teeth","For transmitting nerve impulses and maintaining osmotic balance of cells","For muscle concentration and utilization of iron"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Bone and teeth formation, blood clotting, and normal functioning of the heart, nervous system, and muscles"]},{"question":"What are vitamins?","answers":["Essential minerals required in large quantities for survival","Organic food substances required for normal growth and healthy development","Substances that provide energy for daily activities","Inorganic substances required for metabolic activities"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Organic food substances required for normal growth and healthy development"]},{"question":"What are the two main classes of vitamins?","answers":["Macronutrients and micronutrients","Roughages and minerals","Fat-soluble vitamins and water-soluble vitamins","Carbohydrates and proteins"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Fat-soluble vitamins and water-soluble vitamins"]},{"question":"Which of the following is a fat-soluble vitamin?","answers":["Vitamin C","Vitamin B2","Vitamin A","Vitamin B12"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Vitamin A"]},{"question":"What is the function of vitamin C?","answers":["For strong bone and teeth formation and development","Aids wound healing and helps to resist infection","For normal growth and proper functioning of the heart and nervous system","For the formation of red blood cells"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Aids wound healing and helps to resist infection"]},{"question":"What is water composed of?","answers":["Carbon, hydrogen, oxygen, and nitrogen","Carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen","Hydrogen and oxygen","Carbon, nitrogen, sulfur, and phosphorus"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Hydrogen and oxygen"]},{"question":"What is the function of water?","answers":["For metabolic activities, digestion of food, maintenance of body temperature, transportation medium, and maintenance of osmotic content of the body tissues","To provide energy for daily activities","To act as a lubricant in the body","To aid in tissue repair"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["For metabolic activities, digestion of food, maintenance of body temperature, transportation medium, and maintenance of osmotic content of the body tissues"]},{"question":"What is physical exercise?","answers":["Any bodily activity that enhances or maintains physical fitness and overall health and wellness","Any bodily activity that aids in tissue repair","Any bodily activity that acts as a lubricant in the body","Any bodily activity that provides energy for daily activities"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Any bodily activity that enhances or maintains physical fitness and overall health and wellness"]},{"question":"What is aerobic exercise?","answers":["Physical activity that uses large muscle groups and increases cardiovascular endurance","Physical activity that stretches and lengthens muscles","Physical activity that focuses on accuracy and agility","Physical activity that is intense and short-term"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Physical activity that uses large muscle groups and increases cardiovascular endurance"]},{"question":"What is anaerobic exercise?","answers":["Physical activity that focuses on accuracy and agility","Physical activity that uses large muscle groups and increases cardiovascular endurance","Physical activity that stretches and lengthens muscles","Strength or resistance training that firms, strengthens, and tones muscles"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Strength or resistance training that firms, strengthens, and tones muscles"]},{"question":"What are the benefits of regular physical exercise?","answers":["Providing energy for daily activities and improving body temperature maintenance","Boosting the immune system, preventing diseases, preventing depression, promoting or maintaining positive self-esteem, and improving mental health","Aiding tissue repair and production of essential enzymes","Improving joint flexibility and reducing the chance of injury"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Boosting the immune system, preventing diseases, preventing depression, promoting or maintaining positive self-esteem, and improving mental health"]},{"question":"How is a balanced diet defined?","answers":["A diet that contains the correct proportion or the right amount of all six classes of substances required by an organism","A diet that provides energy required for daily activities","A diet that provides the necessary cofactors for metabolism","A diet that contains essential nutrients for normal growth and healthy development"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["A diet that contains the correct proportion or the right amount of all six classes of substances required by an organism"]},{"question":"What is nutrient a substance used for?","answers":["Disease prevention","Muscle building","Survival and growth","Energy production"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Survival and growth"]},{"question":"What are the main sources of carbohydrates?","answers":["Yam, rice, maize, millet, guinea corn, potatoes, bread, and garri","Beans, groundnut, and soya beans","Milk, egg, fish, and meat","Palm oil, groundnut, soya-bean oil, and melon oil"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Yam, rice, maize, millet, guinea corn, potatoes, bread, and garri"]},{"question":"What is nutrient deficiency?","answers":["Nutrient deficiency occurs when the body doesn’t absorb the necessary amount of a nutrient.","Nutrient deficiency occurs when the body absorbs an excessive amount of a nutrient.","Nutrient deficiency occurs when the body absorbs an insufficient amount of a nutrient.","Nutrient deficiency occurs when the body absorbs the necessary amount of a nutrient."],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Nutrient deficiency occurs when the body doesn’t absorb the necessary amount of a nutrient."]},{"question":"Which nutrient is important for maintaining strong bones and controlling muscle and nerve function?","answers":["Potassium","Calcium","Iron","Vitamin D"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Calcium"]},{"question":"What are the symptoms of severely low calcium?","answers":["Fatigue, muscle cramps, abnormal heart rhythms, and poor appetite","Headaches, dizziness, and blurred vision","Shortness of breath, chest pain, and coughing","Numbness, tingling, and muscle weakness"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Fatigue, muscle cramps, abnormal heart rhythms, and poor appetite"]},{"question":"What role does vitamin D play in the body?","answers":["Boosts immune system","Supports brain health","Promotes muscle growth","Critical for bone health"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Critical for bone health"]},{"question":"What are possible symptoms of a vitamin D deficiency?","answers":["Shortness of breath and chest pain","Nausea, vomiting, and loss of appetite","Dizziness, headache, and blurry vision","Vague fatigue and muscle aches or weakness"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Vague fatigue and muscle aches or weakness"]},{"question":"Why might potassium levels become low in the short term?","answers":["Consuming excessive amounts of potassium-rich foods","Diarrhea or vomiting, excessive sweating, or antibiotics","Dehydration and lack of potassium-rich foods in the diet","Inadequate absorption of potassium by the kidneys"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Diarrhea or vomiting, excessive sweating, or antibiotics"]},{"question":"What are symptoms of potassium deficiency?","answers":["Numbness and tingling in the hands and feet","Frequent urination and increased thirst","Joint pain, swelling, and stiffness","Weight loss, muscle weakness, constipation, and abnormal heart rhythm"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Weight loss, muscle weakness, constipation, and abnormal heart rhythm"]},{"question":"What role does iron play in the body?","answers":["Promotes healthy skin and hair","Helps body make red blood cells","Supports nerve function","Regulates blood pressure"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Helps body make red blood cells"]},{"question":"What can cause an iron deficiency?","answers":["Excessive intake of iron-rich foods","Malabsorption of iron in the digestive tract","Long-term use of oral contraceptives","Colon cancer, gastrointestinal conditions, and diverting iron to the fetus during pregnancy"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Colon cancer, gastrointestinal conditions, and diverting iron to the fetus during pregnancy"]},{"question":"What are symptoms of iron deficiency?","answers":["Numbness, tingling, and muscle weakness","Headaches, dizziness, and blurred vision","Fatigue, pale skin, dull and sparse hair","Muscle cramps, abnormal heart rhythms, and poor appetite"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Fatigue, pale skin, dull and sparse hair"]},{"question":"Why is vitamin B12 deficiency becoming more common?","answers":["Exposure to environmental toxins","Increasing number of vegans and people who've had weight loss surgery","Poor diet choices","Genetic predisposition"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Increasing number of vegans and people who've had weight loss surgery"]},{"question":"What are symptoms of severe vitamin B12 deficiency?","answers":["Bowel irregularities and abdominal pain","Numbness in the legs, hands, or feet; problems with walking and balance; anemia; fatigue; weakness; a swollen, inflamed tongue; memory loss; paranoia; and hallucinations","Chest pain, shortness of breath, and rapid heart rate","Sudden vision loss and eye pain"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Numbness in the legs, hands, or feet; problems with walking and balance; anemia; fatigue; weakness; a swollen, inflamed tongue; memory loss; paranoia; and hallucinations"]},{"question":"Which vitamin is particularly important for women of childbearing age?","answers":["Vitamin B12","Folate or folic acid","Vitamin D","Vitamin C"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Folate or folic acid"]},{"question":"What can a folate deficiency cause?","answers":["Muscle weakness, joint pain, and fatigue","Physical and mental developmental delays in children","Decrease in the total number of cells, large red blood cells, and neural tube defects in unborn child","Weight loss, poor appetite, and digestive issues"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Decrease in the total number of cells, large red blood cells, and neural tube defects in unborn child"]},{"question":"Why might someone have a magnesium deficiency?","answers":["Exposure to heavy metals and industrial chemicals","Certain medications, specific health conditions, or excessive alcohol consumption","Eating a magnesium-rich diet with limited variety of other nutrients","Physical inactivity and poor blood circulation"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Certain medications, specific health conditions, or excessive alcohol consumption"]},{"question":"What are symptoms of magnesium deficiency?","answers":["Frequent urination and excessive thirst","Recurrent infections and slow wound healing","Loss of appetite, nausea and vomiting, fatigue, weakness","Mood swings, irritability, and anxiety"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Loss of appetite, nausea and vomiting, fatigue, weakness"]},{"question":"How can nutritional deficiencies be diagnosed?","answers":["Investigation of patient dietary history, routine blood count (CBC)","Physical examination and visual inspection of symptoms","Genetic testing and hormone level analysis","Radiological imaging and tissue biopsy"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Investigation of patient dietary history, routine blood count (CBC)"]},{"question":"What is the first-line treatment for nutritional deficiencies?","answers":["Antibiotics","Psychological counseling","Surgical intervention","Dietary change"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Dietary change"]},{"question":"What are the possible treatment options for nutritional deficiencies?","answers":["Physical therapy, acupuncture, herbal remedies","Chemotherapy, radiation therapy, and immunotherapy","Invasive procedures like organ transplantation and hormone replacement","Dietary change, supplement, parental administration"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Dietary change, supplement, parental administration"]},{"question":"What are some general symptoms of nutritional deficiencies?","answers":["Fever, headache, and body aches","Digestive issues like bloating and diarrhea","Loss of appetite and weight gain","Pallor (pale skin), fatigue, weakness, trouble breathing"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Pallor (pale skin), fatigue, weakness, trouble breathing"]},{"question":"What are some symptoms that may indicate a nutritional deficiency?","answers":["Usual food craving, hair loss, periods of light headedness","Memory problems, difficulty concentrating, and confusion","Insomnia, restless leg syndrome, and other sleep disorders","Agitation, aggression, and altered mood"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Usual food craving, hair loss, periods of light headedness"]},{"question":"What are some symptoms of severe nutritional deficiencies?","answers":["Joint pain, swelling, and stiffness","Persistent cough, shortness of breath, wheezing","Constipation, sleepiness, heart palpitations","Sudden vision loss and eye pain"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Constipation, sleepiness, heart palpitations"]},{"question":"Which of the following symptoms is associated with nutritional deficiencies?","answers":["Bruising and bleeding easily","Feeling faint or fainting","Skin rashes, itching, and hives","Abdominal pain and cramping"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Feeling faint or fainting"]},{"question":"What are some symptoms that women may experience as a result of nutritional deficiencies?","answers":["Fluctuating body temperature and excessive sweating","Chest pain, palpitations, and anxiety","Poor concentration, menstrual issues (missed periods or very heavy cycles)","Joint swelling, redness, and tenderness"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Poor concentration, menstrual issues (missed periods or very heavy cycles)"]},{"question":"What is malaria?","answers":["Malaria is a fungal infection caused by inhaling spores from the environment.","Malaria is a viral infection transmitted through direct contact with infected individuals.","Malaria is a mosquito-borne infectious disease caused by parasitic protozoan belonging to the genus Plasmodium.","Malaria is a bacterial infection caused by exposure to contaminated water."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Malaria is a mosquito-borne infectious disease caused by parasitic protozoan belonging to the genus Plasmodium."]},{"question":"How is malaria transmitted?","answers":["Malaria is transmitted through breathing in contaminated air.","Malaria is transmitted through direct contact with an infected person's bodily fluids.","Malaria is transmitted through the bite of an infected female Anopheles mosquito.","Malaria is transmitted through contaminated food and water."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Malaria is transmitted through the bite of an infected female Anopheles mosquito."]},{"question":"What are the common symptoms of malaria?","answers":["The common symptoms of malaria include fever, fatigue, vomiting, and headaches.","The common symptoms of malaria include abdominal pain, diarrhea, and nausea.","The common symptoms of malaria include joint pain, muscle aches, and rash.","The common symptoms of malaria include cough, runny nose, and sore throat."],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["The common symptoms of malaria include fever, fatigue, vomiting, and headaches."]},{"question":"How long after a mosquito bite do malaria symptoms usually appear?","answers":["Malaria symptoms usually appear within a few hours after being bitten by an infected mosquito.","Malaria symptoms usually appear ten to fifteen days after being bitten by an infected mosquito.","Malaria symptoms usually appear three to five days after being bitten by an infected mosquito.","Malaria symptoms usually appear one to two days after being bitten by an infected mosquito."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Malaria symptoms usually appear ten to fifteen days after being bitten by an infected mosquito."]},{"question":"What are the severe criteria for classifying malaria according to the WHO?","answers":["The severe criteria for classifying malaria include severe headache, high fever, and rapid breathing.","The severe criteria for classifying malaria include sore throat, chest pain, and swollen lymph nodes.","The severe criteria for classifying malaria include skin rash, joint swelling, and muscle weakness.","The severe criteria for classifying malaria include decreased consciousness, significant weakness, inability to feed, two or more convulsions, low blood pressure, breathing problems, circulatory shock, kidney failure or hemoglobin in the urine, bleeding problems or hemoglobin less than 50 g/L, pulmonary edema, blood glucose less than 2.2 mmol/L, acidosis or lactate levels of greater than 5 mmol/L, a parasite level in the blood of greater than 100,000 per microlitre in low-intensity transmission areas or 250,000 per microlitre in high-intensity transmission areas, and cerebral malaria presenting with neurological symptoms including coma or a coma that lasts longer than 30 minutes after a seizure."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["The severe criteria for classifying malaria include decreased consciousness, significant weakness, inability to feed, two or more convulsions, low blood pressure, breathing problems, circulatory shock, kidney failure or hemoglobin in the urine, bleeding problems or hemoglobin less than 50 g/L, pulmonary edema, blood glucose less than 2.2 mmol/L, acidosis or lactate levels of greater than 5 mmol/L, a parasite level in the blood of greater than 100,000 per microlitre in low-intensity transmission areas or 250,000 per microlitre in high-intensity transmission areas, and cerebral malaria presenting with neurological symptoms including coma or a coma that lasts longer than 30 minutes after a seizure."]},{"question":"Which species of Plasmodium causes the majority of deaths from malaria?","answers":["P. vivax causes the majority of deaths from malaria.","P. ovale causes the majority of deaths from malaria.","P. malariae causes the majority of deaths from malaria.","P. falciparum causes the majority of deaths from malaria."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["P. falciparum causes the majority of deaths from malaria."]},{"question":"What is paroxysm?","answers":["Paroxysm is a condition characterized by inflammation of the lungs in malaria.","Paroxysm is a severe form of malaria that can cause coma and seizures.","Paroxysm is a type of skin rash associated with malaria.","Paroxysm is a cyclical occurrence of sudden coldness followed by shivering, fever, and sweating, commonly observed in malaria infections."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Paroxysm is a cyclical occurrence of sudden coldness followed by shivering, fever, and sweating, commonly observed in malaria infections."]},{"question":"How can malaria be prevented?","answers":["Malaria can be prevented by vaccination against the Plasmodium parasites.","Malaria can be prevented by medications, mosquito elimination, and the prevention of mosquito bites.","Malaria can be prevented by wearing long-sleeved clothing and using insect repellent.","Malaria can be prevented by avoiding outdoor activities during peak mosquito hours."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Malaria can be prevented by medications, mosquito elimination, and the prevention of mosquito bites."]},{"question":"What is an airborne disease?","answers":["An airborne disease is any disease that is caused by exposure to contaminated water.","An airborne disease is any disease that is caused by coming in contact with infected surfaces.","An airborne disease is any disease that is caused by pathogens and transmitted through the air.","An airborne disease is any disease that is caused by the inhalation of toxic chemicals."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["An airborne disease is any disease that is caused by pathogens and transmitted through the air."]},{"question":"What can cause inflammation in the respiratory system due to airborne pathogens?","answers":["The inhalation of airborne pathogens can cause inflammation in the digestive system.","The inhalation of airborne pathogens can cause inflammation in the skin and eyes.","The inhalation of airborne pathogens can cause inflammation in the cardiovascular system.","The inhalation of airborne pathogens can cause inflammation in the nose, throat, sinuses, and lungs."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["The inhalation of airborne pathogens can cause inflammation in the nose, throat, sinuses, and lungs."]},{"question":"What plays a significant role in airborne diseases?","answers":["Air pollution plays a significant role in airborne diseases, particularly in relation to asthma.","Animal bites and scratches play a significant role in airborne diseases, particularly in relation to rabies.","Food contamination plays a significant role in airborne diseases, particularly in relation to gastroenteritis.","Direct contact with infected individuals plays a significant role in airborne diseases, particularly in relation to colds and flu."],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Air pollution plays a significant role in airborne diseases, particularly in relation to asthma."]},{"question":"Which of the following infections can spread by airborne transmission?","answers":["Anthrax, chickenpox, and smallpox can spread by airborne transmission.","Tuberculosis, pneumonia, and bronchitis can spread by airborne transmission.","Influenza, measles, and tuberculosis can spread by airborne transmission.","Cryptococcosis, cryptococcus, and cryptococcal meningitis can spread by airborne transmission."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Influenza, measles, and tuberculosis can spread by airborne transmission."]},{"question":"What are the causes of airborne diseases?","answers":["Airborne diseases can be caused by inhalation of environmental pollutants and toxins.","Airborne diseases can be caused by direct physical contact with an infected person's body fluids.","Airborne diseases can be caused by exposure to contaminated food and water.","Airborne diseases can be caused by exposure to an infected patient or animal through the mouth, nose, cut, or needle puncture."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Airborne diseases can be caused by exposure to an infected patient or animal through the mouth, nose, cut, or needle puncture."]},{"question":"How can airborne diseases be prevented?","answers":["Airborne diseases can be prevented by maintaining good personal hygiene and cleanliness.","Airborne diseases can be prevented by washing hands, getting regular immunizations, wearing respiratory protection, and limiting exposure to infected patients.","Airborne diseases can be prevented by taking antibiotics and antiviral medications.","Airborne diseases can be prevented by avoiding crowded places and public transportation."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Airborne diseases can be prevented by washing hands, getting regular immunizations, wearing respiratory protection, and limiting exposure to infected patients."]},{"question":"What is the treatment for malaria?","answers":["Malaria is treated with antibiotics to eliminate the bacterial infection.","Malaria is treated with antiviral medications to stop the replication of the viruses.","Malaria is treated with antimalarial medications, but the specific treatment depends on the type and severity of the disease.","Malaria is treated with steroids to reduce inflammation and relieve symptoms."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Malaria is treated with antimalarial medications, but the specific treatment depends on the type and severity of the disease."]},{"question":"Which medication is most effective for treating P. falciparum infection?","answers":["The most effective treatment for P. falciparum infection is the use of cholchicine.","The most effective treatment for P. falciparum infection is the use of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs).","The most effective treatment for P. falciparum infection is the use of artemisinin combination therapy (ACT) in combination with other antimalarials.","The most effective treatment for P. falciparum infection is the use of corticosteroids."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["The most effective treatment for P. falciparum infection is the use of artemisinin combination therapy (ACT) in combination with other antimalarials."]},{"question":"How is severe malaria usually treated?","answers":["Severe malaria is usually treated with corticosteroids and immunosuppressive drugs.","Severe malaria is usually treated with intravenous antimalarial drugs, such as artesunate.","Severe malaria is usually treated with oral antimalarial medications.","Severe malaria is usually treated with supportive care and symptomatic relief measures."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Severe malaria is usually treated with intravenous antimalarial drugs, such as artesunate."]},{"question":"Why is early treatment of P. vivax malaria important?","answers":["Early treatment of P. vivax malaria is important to reduce the severity of symptoms.","Early treatment of P. vivax malaria is important to prevent complications and long-term effects.","Early treatment of P. vivax malaria is important to clear both the blood stages and the liver forms of the parasites.","Early treatment of P. vivax malaria is important to prevent the spread of the infection."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Early treatment of P. vivax malaria is important to clear both the blood stages and the liver forms of the parasites."]},{"question":"What complications can occur in severe P. falciparum malaria?","answers":["Complications of severe P. falciparum malaria include joint inflammation and severe muscle pain.","Complications of severe P. falciparum malaria include gastrointestinal bleeding and ulcers.","Complications of severe P. falciparum malaria include respiratory distress, renal failure, cerebral malaria, and blackwater fever.","Complications of severe P. falciparum malaria include skin rashes and itching."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Complications of severe P. falciparum malaria include respiratory distress, renal failure, cerebral malaria, and blackwater fever."]},{"question":"How does air pollution contribute to airborne diseases?","answers":["Air pollution increases inflammation in the respiratory system, making individuals more susceptible to airborne diseases.","Air pollution contains pathogenic microorganisms that cause airborne diseases.","Air pollution directly damages the respiratory system, leading to airborne diseases.","Air pollution weakens the immune system, making individuals more susceptible to airborne diseases."],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Air pollution increases inflammation in the respiratory system, making individuals more susceptible to airborne diseases."]},{"question":"What is the main mode of transmission for airborne diseases?","answers":["The main mode of transmission for airborne diseases is through contaminated food and water.","The main mode of transmission for airborne diseases is through the inhalation of aerosol particles or droplets containing the pathogen.","The main mode of transmission for airborne diseases is through exposure to the body fluids of an infected person.","The main mode of transmission for airborne diseases is direct physical contact with an infected person."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["The main mode of transmission for airborne diseases is through the inhalation of aerosol particles or droplets containing the pathogen."]},{"question":"What is the relationship between air pollution and asthma?","answers":["Air pollution cures asthma and helps to improve lung function.","Air pollution is linked to asthma and can exacerbate symptoms or trigger asthma attacks.","Air pollution has no impact on asthma or respiratory health.","Air pollution only affects individuals with pre-existing respiratory conditions."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Air pollution is linked to asthma and can exacerbate symptoms or trigger asthma attacks."]},{"question":"What are the symptoms common to all malaria species?","answers":["The symptoms common to all malaria species are skin rashes and itching.","The symptoms common to all malaria species are joint pain and muscle aches.","The symptoms common to all malaria species are similar to flu-like symptoms and can resemble other conditions such as septicemia, gastroenteritis, and viral diseases.","The symptoms common to all malaria species are chest pain and shortness of breath."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["The symptoms common to all malaria species are similar to flu-like symptoms and can resemble other conditions such as septicemia, gastroenteritis, and viral diseases."]},{"question":"What are the severe criteria for classifying cerebral malaria?","answers":["Cerebral malaria is classified as severe if it causes severe headache and neck stiffness.","Cerebral malaria is classified as severe if it presents with neurological symptoms, including coma or a coma that lasts longer than 30 minutes after a seizure.","Cerebral malaria is classified as severe if it results in visible parasites in the blood.","Cerebral malaria is classified as severe if it leads to visual disturbances and retinal damage."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Cerebral malaria is classified as severe if it presents with neurological symptoms, including coma or a coma that lasts longer than 30 minutes after a seizure."]},{"question":"What is the characteristic cyclical occurrence observed in malaria infections?","answers":["The characteristic cyclical occurrence observed in malaria infections is paroxysm, which involves sudden coldness followed by shivering, fever, and sweating.","The characteristic cyclical occurrence observed in malaria infections is vomiting and diarrhea.","The characteristic cyclical occurrence observed in malaria infections is skin discoloration and yellowing.","The characteristic cyclical occurrence observed in malaria infections is severe headache and dizziness."],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["The characteristic cyclical occurrence observed in malaria infections is paroxysm, which involves sudden coldness followed by shivering, fever, and sweating."]},{"question":"Which population is most at risk of complications from malaria?","answers":["Individuals with pre-existing lung diseases are most at risk of complications from malaria.","Pregnant women are most at risk of complications from malaria, including stillbirths, infant mortality, abortion, and low birth weight.","Elderly individuals over 65 years old are most at risk of complications from malaria.","Children under 5 years old are most at risk of complications from malaria."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Pregnant women are most at risk of complications from malaria, including stillbirths, infant mortality, abortion, and low birth weight."]},{"question":"What is the impact of climate change on malaria transmission?","answers":["Climate change has no impact on malaria transmission.","Climate change has significantly reduced malaria transmission worldwide.","Climate change has increased the prevalence of malaria in certain regions.","Climate change is likely to affect malaria transmission, but the severity and geographic distribution of such effects is currently uncertain."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Climate change is likely to affect malaria transmission, but the severity and geographic distribution of such effects is currently uncertain."]},{"question":"What is the recommended treatment for severe malaria?","answers":["The recommended treatment for severe malaria is supportive care and symptomatic relief measures.","The recommended treatment for severe malaria is oral antimalarial medications.","The recommended treatment for severe malaria is the intravenous use of antimalarial drugs, with artesunate being superior to quinine.","The recommended treatment for severe malaria is surgical intervention and blood transfusion."],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["The recommended treatment for severe malaria is the intravenous use of antimalarial drugs, with artesunate being superior to quinine."]},{"question":"Why is regular hand washing important in preventing airborne diseases?","answers":["Regular hand washing helps to boost the immune system and prevent airborne diseases.","Regular hand washing helps to remove pathogens from the hands and prevent their transmission to the mouth, nose, or eyes.","Regular hand washing helps to reduce air pollution and minimize the risk of airborne diseases.","Regular hand washing helps to eliminate airborne pathogens in the surrounding environment."],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Regular hand washing helps to remove pathogens from the hands and prevent their transmission to the mouth, nose, or eyes."]},{"question":"What are the classifications of hypertension?","answers":["Hypertension is always caused by an underlying medical condition","Hypertension can only be classified as either idiopathic or symptomatic","Hypertension has only one classification","Hypertension is classified as either primary (essential) hypertension or secondary hypertension. About 90–95% of cases are categorized as primary hypertension, defined as high blood pressure with no obvious underlying cause. The remaining 5–10% of cases are categorized as secondary hypertension, defined as hypertension caused by identifiable conditions such as kidney disease, narrowing of the aorta or kidney arteries, or endocrine disorders such as excess aldosterone or excess cortisol."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Hypertension is classified as either primary (essential) hypertension or secondary hypertension. About 90–95% of cases are categorized as primary hypertension, defined as high blood pressure with no obvious underlying cause. The remaining 5–10% of cases are categorized as secondary hypertension, defined as hypertension caused by identifiable conditions such as kidney disease, narrowing of the aorta or kidney arteries, or endocrine disorders such as excess aldosterone or excess cortisol."]},{"question":"What are the signs and symptoms of pre-eclampsia in pregnancy?","answers":["Headache, visual disturbance (often \"flashing lights\"), vomiting, epigastric pain, and edema","Fever, chills, cough","Back pain, joint pain, muscle aches","Fatigue, dizziness, fainting"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Headache, visual disturbance (often \"flashing lights\"), vomiting, epigastric pain, and edema"]},{"question":"How can hypertension be prevented?","answers":["Consuming caffeine","Smoking cigarettes","Not exercising","Maintain normal body weight for adults (e.g. body mass index 20–25 kg/m2), Reduce dietary sodium intake to <100 mmol/ day (<6 g of sodium chloride or <2.4 g of sodium per day), Engage in regular aerobic physical activity such as brisk walking (≥30 min per day, most days of the week), Limit alcohol consumption to no more than 3 units/day in men and no more than 2 units/day in women, Consume a diet rich in fruit and vegetables (e.g. at least five portions per day);"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Maintain normal body weight for adults (e.g. body mass index 20–25 kg/m2), Reduce dietary sodium intake to <100 mmol/ day (<6 g of sodium chloride or <2.4 g of sodium per day), Engage in regular aerobic physical activity such as brisk walking (≥30 min per day, most days of the week), Limit alcohol consumption to no more than 3 units/day in men and no more than 2 units/day in women, Consume a diet rich in fruit and vegetables (e.g. at least five portions per day);"]},{"question":"What are the main symptoms of hypertension in children?","answers":["Fever, cough, runny nose","Abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting","Rash, joint pain, swollen lymph nodes","Failure to thrive, seizures, irritability, lack of energy, and difficulty breathing can be associated with hypertension in neonates and young infants. In older infants and children, hypertension can cause headache, unexplained irritability, fatigue, failure to thrive, blurred vision, nosebleeds, and facial paralysis."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Failure to thrive, seizures, irritability, lack of energy, and difficulty breathing can be associated with hypertension in neonates and young infants. In older infants and children, hypertension can cause headache, unexplained irritability, fatigue, failure to thrive, blurred vision, nosebleeds, and facial paralysis."]},{"question":"What are the causes of primary hypertension?","answers":["Hyperthyroidism","Narrowed blood vessels","Kidney disease","Hypertension results from a complex interaction of genes and environmental factors. Numerous common genetic variants with small effects on blood pressure have been identified as well as some rare genetic variants with large effects on blood pressure ,but the genetic basis of hypertension is still poorly understood. Blood pressure rises with aging and the risk of becoming hypertensive in later life is considerable. Several environmental factors influence blood pressure. High salt intake raises the blood pressure in salt sensitive individuals; lack of exercise, obesity, stress, and depression can play a role in individual cases. The possible role of other factors such as caffeine consumption, and vitamin D deficiency are less clear. Insulin resistance, which is common in obesity and is a component of syndrome X (or the metabolic syndrome), is also thought to contribute to hypertension. Events in early life, such as low birth weight, maternal smoking, and lack of breast feeding may be risk factors for adult essential hypertension, although the mechanisms linking these exposures to adult hypertension remain unclear."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Hypertension results from a complex interaction of genes and environmental factors. Numerous common genetic variants with small effects on blood pressure have been identified as well as some rare genetic variants with large effects on blood pressure ,but the genetic basis of hypertension is still poorly understood. Blood pressure rises with aging and the risk of becoming hypertensive in later life is considerable. Several environmental factors influence blood pressure. High salt intake raises the blood pressure in salt sensitive individuals; lack of exercise, obesity, stress, and depression can play a role in individual cases. The possible role of other factors such as caffeine consumption, and vitamin D deficiency are less clear. Insulin resistance, which is common in obesity and is a component of syndrome X (or the metabolic syndrome), is also thought to contribute to hypertension. Events in early life, such as low birth weight, maternal smoking, and lack of breast feeding may be risk factors for adult essential hypertension, although the mechanisms linking these exposures to adult hypertension remain unclear."]},{"question":"What are the main types of sexually transmitted infection?","answers":["Chlamydia, Herpes, Human papillomavirus (HPV), Gonorrhoea, Syphilis, Trichomoniasis, HIV","Hepatitis A","Malaria","Hepatitis B"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Chlamydia, Herpes, Human papillomavirus (HPV), Gonorrhoea, Syphilis, Trichomoniasis, HIV"]},{"question":"Which STI vaccine protects against some types of HPV?","answers":["Hepatitis B vaccine","Influenza vaccine","Hepatitis A vaccine","There are also two vaccines available for women (Cervix and Gardasil) that protect against the types of HPV that cause cervical cancer."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["There are also two vaccines available for women (Cervix and Gardasil) that protect against the types of HPV that cause cervical cancer."]},{"question":"What are the signs and symptoms of gonorrhoea in men?","answers":["Vaginal discharge","Lower abdominal pain","Sore throat","Symptoms in men include pain when urinating, and abnormal discharge from their penis. If left untreated in both men and women, Chlamydia can infect the urinary tract and potentially lead to pelvic inflammatory disease (PID)."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Symptoms in men include pain when urinating, and abnormal discharge from their penis. If left untreated in both men and women, Chlamydia can infect the urinary tract and potentially lead to pelvic inflammatory disease (PID)."]},{"question":"How is syphilis transmitted?","answers":["Through casual contact","Through respiratory droplets","Syphilis is an STI caused by a bacterium. If acquired, syphilis needs to be treated adequately; otherwise it can cause long-term complications and death. Clinical manifestations of syphilis include the ulceration of the uro-genital tract, mouth or rectum; if left untreated the symptoms worsen.","Through blood transfusion"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Syphilis is an STI caused by a bacterium. If acquired, syphilis needs to be treated adequately; otherwise it can cause long-term complications and death. Clinical manifestations of syphilis include the ulceration of the uro-genital tract, mouth or rectum; if left untreated the symptoms worsen."]},{"question":"What are the stages of HIV progression if left untreated?","answers":["The stages include primary infection, asymptomatic infection, symptomatic infection, and AIDS. In the primary infection stage, an individual will have flu like symptoms (headache, fatigue, fever, muscle aches) for about 2 weeks. In the asymptomatic stage, symptoms usually disappear, and the patient can remain asymptomatic for years. When HIV progresses to the symptomatic stage, the immune system is weakened, and has a low cell count of CD4+ T Cells. When the HIV infection becomes life-threatening, it is called AIDS. People with AIDS fall prey to opportunistic infections and die as a result.","Seroconversion, clinical latency, AIDS","Exposure, seroconversion, seroreversion","Incubation period, acute infection, chronic infection"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["The stages include primary infection, asymptomatic infection, symptomatic infection, and AIDS. In the primary infection stage, an individual will have flu like symptoms (headache, fatigue, fever, muscle aches) for about 2 weeks. In the asymptomatic stage, symptoms usually disappear, and the patient can remain asymptomatic for years. When HIV progresses to the symptomatic stage, the immune system is weakened, and has a low cell count of CD4+ T Cells. When the HIV infection becomes life-threatening, it is called AIDS. People with AIDS fall prey to opportunistic infections and die as a result."]},{"question":"What are the symptoms of trichomoniasis?","answers":["Vaginal itching and burning","Genital sores and rashes","Trichomoniasis affects both women and men, but symptoms are more common in women most patients are treated with an antibiotic called metronidazole, which is very effective.","Lower abdominal pain"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Trichomoniasis affects both women and men, but symptoms are more common in women most patients are treated with an antibiotic called metronidazole, which is very effective."]},{"question":"Which STI can cause infertility in women if left untreated?","answers":["HIV","Chlamydia","Gonorrhoea","Genital warts"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Chlamydia"]},{"question":"What are the proper steps for male condom usage?","answers":["Wash condom with soap before use","Use expired condoms","Not putting the condom on too tight at the end, and leaving 1.5 cm (3/4 inch) room at the tip for ejaculation. Putting the condom on snug can and often does lead to failure. Wearing a condom too loose can defeat the barrier. Avoiding inverting or spilling a condom once worn, whether it has ejaculate in it or not. If a user attempts to unroll the condom, but realizes they have it on the wrong side, then this condom should be discarded. Being careful with the condom if handling it with long nails. Avoiding the use of oil-based lubricants (or anything with oil in it) with latex condoms, as oil can eat holes into them. Using flavoured condoms for oral sex only, as the sugar in the flavouring can lead to yeast infections if used to penetrate.","Reuse condom multiple times"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Not putting the condom on too tight at the end, and leaving 1.5 cm (3/4 inch) room at the tip for ejaculation. Putting the condom on snug can and often does lead to failure. Wearing a condom too loose can defeat the barrier. Avoiding inverting or spilling a condom once worn, whether it has ejaculate in it or not. If a user attempts to unroll the condom, but realizes they have it on the wrong side, then this condom should be discarded. Being careful with the condom if handling it with long nails. Avoiding the use of oil-based lubricants (or anything with oil in it) with latex condoms, as oil can eat holes into them. Using flavoured condoms for oral sex only, as the sugar in the flavouring can lead to yeast infections if used to penetrate."]},{"question":"What are the symptoms of organs dysfunction?","answers":["Fever","Runny nose","Cough","Fatigue and loss of appetite, Yellowing of the skin, Excessive weakness, Yellowing of the eyes ball, Constant pain in upper abdomen, Nausea, Weakness in bone, Chest pain, Decrease in immunity, Weakness in muscles due to body fluid imbalance, Increase in heart rate, Reduction in ability to focus, Loss of memory, Obstruction to the air path, A decline in urine output"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Fatigue and loss of appetite, Yellowing of the skin, Excessive weakness, Yellowing of the eyes ball, Constant pain in upper abdomen, Nausea, Weakness in bone, Chest pain, Decrease in immunity, Weakness in muscles due to body fluid imbalance, Increase in heart rate, Reduction in ability to focus, Loss of memory, Obstruction to the air path, A decline in urine output"]},{"question":"How is trichomoniasis transmitted?","answers":["Through respiratory droplets","Trichomoniasis is a common STI that is caused by infection with a protozoan parasite called Trichomonasvaginalis.","Through casual contact","Through fecal-oral route"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Trichomoniasis is a common STI that is caused by infection with a protozoan parasite called Trichomonasvaginalis."]},{"question":"What are the causes of secondary hypertension?","answers":["Lack of exercise","Secondary hypertension results from an identifiable cause. Kidney disease is the most common secondary cause of hypertension. Hypertension can also be caused by endocrine conditions, such as Cushing's syndrome, hyperthyroidism, hypothyroidism, acromegaly, Conn's syndrome or hyperaldosteronism, hyperparathyroidism and pheochromocytoma. Other causes of secondary hypertension include obesity, sleep apnea, pregnancy, coarctation of the aorta, excessive liquorice consumption and certain prescription medicines, herbal remedies and illegal drugs.","Stress","High salt diet"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Secondary hypertension results from an identifiable cause. Kidney disease is the most common secondary cause of hypertension. Hypertension can also be caused by endocrine conditions, such as Cushing's syndrome, hyperthyroidism, hypothyroidism, acromegaly, Conn's syndrome or hyperaldosteronism, hyperparathyroidism and pheochromocytoma. Other causes of secondary hypertension include obesity, sleep apnea, pregnancy, coarctation of the aorta, excessive liquorice consumption and certain prescription medicines, herbal remedies and illegal drugs."]},{"question":"What is the recommended diagnostic test for chlamydia and gonorrhoea?","answers":["Rapid plasma reagin test","Gram staining","Nucleic acid amplification tests. This can be done on either urine in both men and women, vaginal or cervical swabs in women, or urethral swabs in men.","Wet mount microscopy"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Nucleic acid amplification tests. This can be done on either urine in both men and women, vaginal or cervical swabs in women, or urethral swabs in men."]},{"question":"Why are nucleic acid amplification tests recommended for diagnosis of gonorrhoea and chlamydia?","answers":["These are the recommended method of diagnosis for gonorrhea and chlamydia. This can be done on either urine in both men and women, vaginal or cervical swabs in women, or urethral swabs in men.","Fast turnaround time","Inexpensive","High sensitivity and specificity"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["These are the recommended method of diagnosis for gonorrhea and chlamydia. This can be done on either urine in both men and women, vaginal or cervical swabs in women, or urethral swabs in men."]},{"question":"How is herpes simplex virus spread?","answers":["Through blood transfusion","Through respiratory droplets","Through fecal-oral route","Herpes is spread through skin contact with a person infected with the virus. The virus affects the areas where it entered the body. This can occur through kissing, vaginal intercourse, oral sex or anal sex. The virus is most infectious during times when there are visible symptoms, however those who are asymptomatic can still spread the virus through skin contact."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Herpes is spread through skin contact with a person infected with the virus. The virus affects the areas where it entered the body. This can occur through kissing, vaginal intercourse, oral sex or anal sex. The virus is most infectious during times when there are visible symptoms, however those who are asymptomatic can still spread the virus through skin contact."]},{"question":"What is patient-delivered partner therapy?","answers":["An option for treating partners of patients (index cases) diagnosed with chlamydia or gonorrhea is patient-delivered partner therapy, which is the clinical practice of treating the sex partners of index cases by providing prescriptions or medications to the patient to take to his/her partner without the health care provider first examining the partner.","Contact tracing of sexual partners","Expedited partner therapy without examination","Mass treatment of communities"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["An option for treating partners of patients (index cases) diagnosed with chlamydia or gonorrhea is patient-delivered partner therapy, which is the clinical practice of treating the sex partners of index cases by providing prescriptions or medications to the patient to take to his/her partner without the health care provider first examining the partner."]},{"question":"What are some signs of secondary hypertension?","answers":["Fatigue","Diseases that lead to secondary hypertension often have characteristic signs and symptoms. For example, Cushing's syndrome is frequently characterized by truncal obesity, glucose intolerance, moon face, a hump of fat behind the neck/shoulder, and purple abdominal stretch marks. If a person has hypertension and also experiences weight loss with increased appetite, fast heart rate, bulging eyes, and tremor, this may suggest a diagnosis of hyperthyroidism. A localized bruit over the middle of the abdomen to the left or right of the midline is consistent with renal artery stenosis. Hypertension in the context of decreased blood pressure in the lower extremities and/or delayed or absent femoral arterial pulses is suggestive of coarctation of the aorta. A person with a pheochromocytoma may have episodes of hypertension accompanied by headache, palpitations, pale appearance, and excessive sweating.","Nausea","Headache"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Diseases that lead to secondary hypertension often have characteristic signs and symptoms. For example, Cushing's syndrome is frequently characterized by truncal obesity, glucose intolerance, moon face, a hump of fat behind the neck/shoulder, and purple abdominal stretch marks. If a person has hypertension and also experiences weight loss with increased appetite, fast heart rate, bulging eyes, and tremor, this may suggest a diagnosis of hyperthyroidism. A localized bruit over the middle of the abdomen to the left or right of the midline is consistent with renal artery stenosis. Hypertension in the context of decreased blood pressure in the lower extremities and/or delayed or absent femoral arterial pulses is suggestive of coarctation of the aorta. A person with a pheochromocytoma may have episodes of hypertension accompanied by headache, palpitations, pale appearance, and excessive sweating."]},{"question":"How can sexually transmitted diseases be managed?","answers":["High-risk exposure such as that which occurs in rape cases may be treated preventatively using antibiotic combinations such as azithromycin, cefixime and metronidazole.","Patient education","Vaccination","Barrier protection"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["High-risk exposure such as that which occurs in rape cases may be treated preventatively using antibiotic combinations such as azithromycin, cefixime and metronidazole."]},{"question":"What are the objectives of lifestyle modifications for hypertension?","answers":["Smoke cigarettes","Drink more alcohol","Increase salt intake","The 2004 British Hypertension Society guidelines proposed the following lifestyle changes consistent with those outlined by the US National High BP Education Program in 2002for the primary prevention of hypertension: Maintain normal body weight for adults (e.g. body mass index 20–25 kg/m2), Reduce dietary sodium intake to <100 mmol/ day (<6 g of sodium chloride or <2.4 g of sodium per day), Engage in regular aerobic physical activity such as brisk walking (≥30 min per day, most days of the week), Limit alcohol consumption to no more than 3 units/day in men and no more than 2 units/day in women, Consume a diet rich in fruit and vegetables (e.g. at least five portions per day);"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["The 2004 British Hypertension Society guidelines proposed the following lifestyle changes consistent with those outlined by the US National High BP Education Program in 2002for the primary prevention of hypertension: Maintain normal body weight for adults (e.g. body mass index 20–25 kg/m2), Reduce dietary sodium intake to <100 mmol/ day (<6 g of sodium chloride or <2.4 g of sodium per day), Engage in regular aerobic physical activity such as brisk walking (≥30 min per day, most days of the week), Limit alcohol consumption to no more than 3 units/day in men and no more than 2 units/day in women, Consume a diet rich in fruit and vegetables (e.g. at least five portions per day);"]},{"question":"What are the signs and symptoms of syphilis?","answers":["Rash","Sore throat","Fatigue","Clinical manifestations of syphilis include the ulceration of the uro-genital tract, mouth or rectum; if left untreated the symptoms worsen."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Clinical manifestations of syphilis include the ulceration of the uro-genital tract, mouth or rectum; if left untreated the symptoms worsen."]},{"question":"What are the main characteristics of cancer?","answers":["Abnormal cell growth","Formation of discernible mass","Potential to invade other parts of body","Self-sufficiency in growth signalling, Insensitivity to anti-growth signals, Evasion of apoptosis, Enabling of a limitless replicative potential, Induction and sustainment of angiogenesis, Activation of metastasis and invasion of tissue."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Self-sufficiency in growth signalling, Insensitivity to anti-growth signals, Evasion of apoptosis, Enabling of a limitless replicative potential, Induction and sustainment of angiogenesis, Activation of metastasis and invasion of tissue."]},{"question":"What are the local effects of cancer?","answers":["Fatigue","Weight loss","Nausea","Masses in breasts or testicles may be easily felt. Ulceration can cause bleeding that, if it occurs in the lung, will lead to coughing up blood, in the bowels to anaemia or rectal bleeding, in the bladder to blood in the urine, and in the uterus to vaginal bleeding. Although localized pain may occur in advanced cancer, the initial swelling is usually painless. Some cancers can cause a build-up of fluid within the chest or abdomen"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Masses in breasts or testicles may be easily felt. Ulceration can cause bleeding that, if it occurs in the lung, will lead to coughing up blood, in the bowels to anaemia or rectal bleeding, in the bladder to blood in the urine, and in the uterus to vaginal bleeding. Although localized pain may occur in advanced cancer, the initial swelling is usually painless. Some cancers can cause a build-up of fluid within the chest or abdomen"]},{"question":"What are the systemic symptoms of cancer?","answers":["General symptoms occur due to distant effects of the cancer that are not related to direct or metastatic spread. These may include: unintentional weight loss, fever, being excessively tired, and changes to the skin.","Difficulty swallowing","Cough","Bleeding"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["General symptoms occur due to distant effects of the cancer that are not related to direct or metastatic spread. These may include: unintentional weight loss, fever, being excessively tired, and changes to the skin."]},{"question":"What are the causes of cancer syndrome?","answers":["Radiation","Diet","Smoking","Certain inherited mutations in the genes BRCA1 and BRCA2 with a more than 75% risk of breast cancer and ovarian cancer, and hereditary nonpolyposis colorectal cancer (HNPCC or Lynch syndrome), which is present in about 3% of people with colorectal cancer, among others."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Certain inherited mutations in the genes BRCA1 and BRCA2 with a more than 75% risk of breast cancer and ovarian cancer, and hereditary nonpolyposis colorectal cancer (HNPCC or Lynch syndrome), which is present in about 3% of people with colorectal cancer, among others."]},{"question":"Which types of cancer arise from connective tissue?","answers":["Leukemia","Sarcoma","Lymphoma","Carcinoma"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Sarcoma"]},{"question":"Which types of cancer arise from blood forming cells?","answers":["Germ cell tumor","Carcinoma","Sarcoma","Lymphoma and leukemia"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Lymphoma and leukemia"]},{"question":"Which types of cancer are derived from immature precursor cells?","answers":["Germ cell tumor","Blastoma","Carcinoma","Sarcoma"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Blastoma"]},{"question":"Which hormone causes breast cancer?","answers":["Growth hormone","Estrogen and progesterone","Testosterone","Insulin"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Estrogen and progesterone"]},{"question":"Which types of cancer are caused by prolonged sun exposure?","answers":["Lung cancer","Breast cancer","Prostate cancer","Melanoma and other skin malignancies"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Melanoma and other skin malignancies"]},{"question":"Which virus causes cervical cancer?","answers":["Human T-cell leukemia virus","Hepatitis B virus","Human papillomavirus","Epstein-Barr virus"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Human papillomavirus"]},{"question":"Which virus causes liver cancer?","answers":["Kaposi's sarcoma herpesvirus","Hepatitis B and hepatitis C viruses","Epstein-Barr virus","Human papillomavirus"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Hepatitis B and hepatitis C viruses"]},{"question":"Which physical agent causes mesothelioma?","answers":["Ultraviolet radiation","Electromagnetic fields","Ionizing radiation","Prolonged exposure to asbestos"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Prolonged exposure to asbestos"]},{"question":"Which medication helps reduce breast cancer risk in high risk women?","answers":["Tamoxifen or raloxifene","Ibuprofen","Aspirin","Paracetamol"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Tamoxifen or raloxifene"]},{"question":"Which vaccines help prevent which cancers?","answers":["Influenza vaccine prevents lung cancer","BCG vaccine prevents breast cancer","Polio vaccine prevents skin cancer","Human papillomavirus vaccine prevents cervical cancer and Hepatitis B vaccine prevents liver cancer"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Human papillomavirus vaccine prevents cervical cancer and Hepatitis B vaccine prevents liver cancer"]},{"question":"Which infectious agent causes gastric cancer?","answers":["Epstein-Barr virus","Hepatitis B virus","Helicobacter pylori","Human papilloma virus"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Helicobacter pylori"]},{"question":"Which parasite causes bladder cancer?","answers":["Toxoplasma gondii","Trichomonas vaginalis","Plasmodium falciparum","Schistosoma haematobium"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Schistosoma haematobium"]},{"question":"Which parasite causes cholangiocarcinoma?","answers":["Ascaris lumbricoides","Toxoplasma gondii","Opisthorchis viverrini and Clonorchis sinensis","Entamoeba histolytica"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Opisthorchis viverrini and Clonorchis sinensis"]},{"question":"Which radiation causes most non-melanoma skin cancers?","answers":["Non-ionizing ultraviolet radiation","X-rays","Gamma rays","Alpha particles"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Non-ionizing ultraviolet radiation"]},{"question":"Which lifestyle factor increases breast cancer risk the most?","answers":["Physical inactivity","Red meat consumption","Air pollution","Alcohol consumption"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Alcohol consumption"]},{"question":"Which dietary factor reduces liver cancer risk?","answers":["Vegetable consumption","Coffee consumption","Olive oil consumption","Fruit consumption"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Coffee consumption"]},{"question":"Which medication increases lung cancer risk when supplemented?","answers":["Folic acid","Calcium","Beta-Carotene","Vitamin C"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Beta-Carotene"]},{"question":"Which cancer screening method uses examination of a tissue sample?","answers":["CT scans","Pathological examination","X-rays","Blood tests"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Pathological examination"]},{"question":"How are cancers commonly named?","answers":["Using only the cell type","Using only the organ name","Randomly assigned names","Using -carcinoma, -sarcoma or -blastoma as a suffix, with the Latin or Greek word for the organ or tissue of origin as the root"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Using -carcinoma, -sarcoma or -blastoma as a suffix, with the Latin or Greek word for the organ or tissue of origin as the root"]},{"question":"What is the hereditary blood disorder characterized by an abnormality in the oxygen-carrying haemoglobin molecule in red blood cells?","answers":["thalassemia","leukemia","sickle-cell disease","haemophilia"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["sickle-cell disease"]},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT a subtype of sickle-cell disease?","answers":["sickle-cell trait","sickle-beta thalassemia","drepanocytosis","sickle-cell anemia"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["sickle-cell trait"]},{"question":"What leads to a propensity for red blood cells to assume an abnormal, rigid, sickle-like shape under certain circumstances in sickle-cell disease?","answers":["dehydration","infection","This abnormality in the oxygen-carrying hemoglobin molecule in red blood cells.","low oxygen levels"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["This abnormality in the oxygen-carrying hemoglobin molecule in red blood cells."]},{"question":"What is the term used to describe several independent acute conditions occurring in patients with sickle-cell disease?","answers":["vaso-occlusive event","sickle-cell crisis","haemolytic episode","splenic sequestration"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["sickle-cell crisis"]},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT a type of sickle-cell crisis?","answers":["vaso-occlusive crisis","reticulocytopenia crisis","aplastic crisis","splenic sequestration crisis"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["reticulocytopenia crisis"]},{"question":"What causes aplastic crises in sickle-cell patients?","answers":["malaria","hypoxia","bacterial infection","parvovirus B19 infection"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["parvovirus B19 infection"]},{"question":"What treatment is given to sickle-cell patients from birth to 5 years of age?","answers":["hydroxyurea","penicillin daily","blood transfusion","folic acid"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["penicillin daily"]},{"question":"What organ is most commonly affected in sickle-cell patients due to its narrow vessels and function in clearing defective red blood cells?","answers":["kidneys","liver","lungs","spleen"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["spleen"]},{"question":"What is the definition of acute chest syndrome?","answers":["pleural effusion","chest pain only","cough","chest pain, fever, pulmonary infiltrate or focal abnormality, respiratory symptoms, or hypoxemia."],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["chest pain, fever, pulmonary infiltrate or focal abnormality, respiratory symptoms, or hypoxemia."]},{"question":"What test determines the presence of sickle hemoglobin?","answers":["complete blood count","malaria test","sickle solubility test","sickling test"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["sickle solubility test"]},{"question":"What is the only known cure for sickle-cell disease?","answers":["bone marrow transplants","hydroxyurea","blood transfusions","penicillin"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["bone marrow transplants"]},{"question":"What level of hemoglobin is seen on CBC in patients with HbSS sickle-cell disease?","answers":["10-12 g/dl","6-8 g/dl","14-16 g/dl","2-4 g/dl"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["6-8 g/dl"]},{"question":"What drug was the first approved for causative treatment of sickle-cell anemia?","answers":["hydroxyurea","folic acid","penicillin","blood transfusion"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["hydroxyurea"]},{"question":"What complication occurs due to excessive bilirubin production and precipitation in sickle-cell patients?","answers":["priapism","osteomyelitis","cholelithiasis and cholecystitis","stroke"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["cholelithiasis and cholecystitis"]},{"question":"What organ is most at risk for infarction in sickle-cell patients before the end of childhood?","answers":["kidneys","spleen","lungs","liver"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["spleen"]},{"question":"What type of transfusion therapy is used to prevent complications in sickle-cell disease?","answers":["platelet transfusion","chronic red blood cell transfusion therapy","acute plasma exchange","selective red cell apheresis"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["chronic red blood cell transfusion therapy"]},{"question":"What test can be used to induce sickling of red blood cells on a blood film?","answers":["hemolysis","addition of sodium metabisulfite","centrifugation","microscopy"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["addition of sodium metabisulfite"]},{"question":"What increases risk of infections in sickle-cell patients due to loss of functioning spleen tissue?","answers":["encapsulated organisms like Streptococcus pneumoniae","fungi","enteric bacteria","parasites"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["encapsulated organisms like Streptococcus pneumoniae"]},{"question":"What complication can result from a progressive narrowing of blood vessels in sickle-cell patients?","answers":["chest syndrome","stroke","osteomyelitis","priapism"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["stroke"]},{"question":"What type of crisis is considered a medical emergency in sickle-cell patients?","answers":["aplastic crisis","vaso-occlusive crisis","splenic sequestration crisis","hemolytic crisis"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["splenic sequestration crisis"]},{"question":"What test is used to detect abnormal hemoglobin forms electrophoretically?","answers":["hemoglobin electrophoresis","coombs test","xray","CBC"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["hemoglobin electrophoresis"]},{"question":"Why are sickle-cell patients more vulnerable to malaria if living in malaria endemic areas?","answers":["malaria is the most common cause of painful crises in these regions","malaria causes hemolysis in SCD patients","sickle cells weaken immune response to malaria","they lack spleen to fight malaria"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["malaria is the most common cause of painful crises in these regions"]},{"question":"What conditions can trigger an acute chest syndrome in sickle-cell patients?","answers":["only respiratory infection","painful crisis, respiratory infection, bone-marrow embolization, or possibly atelectasis, opiate administration, or surgery","only hypoxia","only pneumonia"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["painful crisis, respiratory infection, bone-marrow embolization, or possibly atelectasis, opiate administration, or surgery"]},{"question":"What complications can occur in the eyes of sickle-cell patients?","answers":["color blindness","cataracts","background retinopathy, proliferative retinopathy, vitreous haemorrhages, and retinal detachments resulting in blindness","glaucoma"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["background retinopathy, proliferative retinopathy, vitreous haemorrhages, and retinal detachments resulting in blindness"]},{"question":"What type of vaso-occlusive pain can occur in sickle-cell patients even without acute episodes?","answers":["neuropathic pain","referred pain","chronic pain","acute pain"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["chronic pain"]},{"question":"What is the most common cause of osteomyelitis in sickle-cell patients?","answers":["Staphylococcus aureus","Streptococcus pneumoniae","Escherichia coli","Salmonella (especially atypical serotypes)"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Salmonella (especially atypical serotypes)"]},{"question":"What is HIV?","answers":["Human immunodeficiency virus syndrome and acquired immune deficiency syndrome","Human immunodeficiency virus infection and acquired immune syndrome","Human immunodeficiency virus infection and acquired immune deficiency syndrome","Human immunodeficiency virus infection and acquired deficiency syndrome"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Human immunodeficiency virus infection and acquired immune deficiency syndrome"]},{"question":"What are the main symptoms of acute HIV infection?","answers":["Fever, large tender lymph nodes, throat inflammation, rash, headache, and sores of the mouth and genitals","Frequent urination, blurry vision, and increased thirst","Weight loss, joint pain, fatigue, and diarrhea","Cough, chest pain, shortness of breath, and fever"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Fever, large tender lymph nodes, throat inflammation, rash, headache, and sores of the mouth and genitals"]},{"question":"What are the main symptoms of AIDS?","answers":["Fatigue, night sweats, and weight loss","Nausea, vomiting, and diarrhea","Fever, sore throat, and body aches","Pneumocystis pneumonia, HIV wasting syndrome, and esophageal candidiasis"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Pneumocystis pneumonia, HIV wasting syndrome, and esophageal candidiasis"]},{"question":"How is HIV transmitted primarily?","answers":["Unprotected sexual intercourse (anal and oral sex), contaminated blood transfusions, hypodermic needles, mother to child during pregnancy, delivery or breastfeeding","Mosquito bites","Sharing utensils or towels","Casual contact with infected individuals"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Unprotected sexual intercourse (anal and oral sex), contaminated blood transfusions, hypodermic needles, mother to child during pregnancy, delivery or breastfeeding"]},{"question":"What is the term for the initial period following the contraction of HIV?","answers":["Early HIV, primary AIDS, or early retroviral syndrome","Chronic HIV, secondary HIV, or chronic retroviral syndrome","Acute HIV, primary HIV, or acute retroviral syndrome","Late HIV, tertiary HIV, or late retroviral syndrome"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Acute HIV, primary HIV, or acute retroviral syndrome"]},{"question":"How can primary HIV be diagnosed before seroconversion?","answers":["Testing for viral load","Measuring HIV antibodies","Measuring HIV-RNA or p24 antigen","Performing a physical examination"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Measuring HIV-RNA or p24 antigen"]},{"question":"What are the stages of HIV infection?","answers":["Asymptomatic infection, chronic infection, and terminal infection","Primary infection, secondary infection, and recurrent infection","Acute infection, clinical latency, and AIDS","Early infection, middle infection, and late infection"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Acute infection, clinical latency, and AIDS"]},{"question":"What is the recommended treatment for HIV?","answers":["Antibiotic therapy","Surgical intervention","Highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART)","Chemotherapy"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART)"]},{"question":"How can HIV transmission be prevented during sexual contact?","answers":["Consistent use of condoms","Fertility awareness methods","Withdrawal method","Abstinence from sexual activity"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Consistent use of condoms"]},{"question":"What is the recommended approach to prevent vertical transmission of HIV?","answers":["Antiviral medications during pregnancy and after birth in the infant, and potentially bottle feeding instead of breastfeeding","Male circumcision","Avoiding pregnancy altogether","Breastfeeding and early weaning"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Antiviral medications during pregnancy and after birth in the infant, and potentially bottle feeding instead of breastfeeding"]},{"question":"Which medication combination is commonly used for HIV treatment?","answers":["Elvitegravir, emtricitabine, tenofovir, and cobicistat","Isoniazid, rifampicin, ethambutol, and pyrazinamide","Ibuprofen, amoxicillin, cetirizine, and lorazepam","Metformin, lisinopril, simvastatin, and levothyroxine"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Elvitegravir, emtricitabine, tenofovir, and cobicistat"]},{"question":"What is the main purpose of HIV screening?","answers":["To diagnose AIDS","To identify specific opportunistic infections","To measure the viral load in an individual","To detect the presence of HIV antibodies"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["To detect the presence of HIV antibodies"]},{"question":"Which type of HIV infection is asymptomatic with a CD4+ T cell count greater than 500 cells per µL of blood?","answers":["Stage II","Primary HIV infection","Stage III","Stage I"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Stage I"]},{"question":"What is the recommended prophylactic therapy for opportunistic infections in people with HIV/AIDS?","answers":["Antiviral therapy","Trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole prophylaxis","Antifungal therapy","Antibacterial therapy"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole prophylaxis"]},{"question":"How can HIV transmission be prevented after a needle-stick injury?","answers":["Post-exposure prophylaxis (PEP)","Surgical intervention","Pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP)","Antiretroviral therapy (ART)"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Post-exposure prophylaxis (PEP)"]},{"question":"What are the main methods of preventing transmission of HIV?","answers":["Safe sex, needle-exchange programs, and treating those who are infected","Isolation of infected individuals","Mandatory HIV testing","Quarantine of infected individuals"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Safe sex, needle-exchange programs, and treating those who are infected"]},{"question":"How do micronutrient supplements contribute to the management of HIV/AIDS?","answers":["They directly target and eliminate the HIV virus","They reduce the side effects of antiretroviral therapy","They stimulate the production of HIV antibodies","They provide additional nutrients that may benefit individuals with the infection"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["They provide additional nutrients that may benefit individuals with the infection"]},{"question":"What are the possible adverse effects of higher intake of vitamin A, zinc, and iron in HIV positive adults?","answers":["Enhanced immune function","Adverse effects","Improved physical strength","Increased healing of opportunistic infections"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Adverse effects"]},{"question":"How does male circumcision affect HIV transmission?","answers":["It reduces the acquisition of HIV by heterosexual men by 38-66% over 24 months","It increases the risk of HIV transmission","It eliminates the risk of HIV transmission completely","It has no effect on HIV transmission"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["It reduces the acquisition of HIV by heterosexual men by 38-66% over 24 months"]},{"question":"What is the main purpose of antiretroviral therapy for HIV/AIDS?","answers":["To cure the infection completely","To reduce the risk of transmission","To prevent opportunistic infections","To slow the progression of the disease"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["To slow the progression of the disease"]},{"question":"What is the most common cancer associated with HIV/AIDS?","answers":["Breast cancer","Colon cancer","Lung cancer","Kaposi's sarcoma"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Kaposi's sarcoma"]},{"question":"How can hepatitis A and B be prevented in individuals at risk of HIV?","answers":["Vaccination","Antiviral therapy","Regular blood tests","Quarantine measures"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Vaccination"]},{"question":"What is the main symptom of primary HIV infection?","answers":["Chronic diarrhea","Severe weight loss","Influenza-like illness or a mononucleosis-like illness","Persistent fever"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Influenza-like illness or a mononucleosis-like illness"]},{"question":"When should post-exposure prophylaxis (PEP) be initiated after exposure to HIV-positive blood or genital secretions?","answers":["Within 1 week","Within 2 weeks","Within 7 days","Within 48 to 72 hours"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Within 48 to 72 hours"]},{"question":"What is the main method of transmission for mother-to-child HIV transmission?","answers":["During pregnancy, delivery, or breastfeeding","During sexual intercourse","Sharing personal items","Coughing or sneezing"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["During pregnancy, delivery, or breastfeeding"]},{"question":"What is the recommended duration of treatment for post-exposure prophylaxis (PEP)?","answers":["Eight weeks","Six weeks","Four weeks","Two weeks"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Four weeks"]},{"question":"What is the WHO system for HIV classification based on?","answers":["Presence of HIV antibodies","Viral load measurements","Number of opportunistic infections","CD4+ T cell count and clinical symptoms"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["CD4+ T cell count and clinical symptoms"]},{"question":"List the plant parts from which drugs are obtained.","answers":["flowers, fruits, bark","Leaves, flowers, fruits, seeds, roots, bark, stem","roots, bark, leaves","leaves, fruits, seeds"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Leaves, flowers, fruits, seeds, roots, bark, stem"]},{"question":"Name the drug obtained from poppy papaver somniferum.","answers":["morphine","codeine","quinine","atropine"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["morphine"]},{"question":"List the animal sources of drugs.","answers":["liver, kidneys, lungs","Pancreas, urine of pregnant women, sheep thyroid, cod liver, anterior pituitary, blood of animals, stomach tissue","heart, intestines, spleen","bones, muscles, tendons"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Pancreas, urine of pregnant women, sheep thyroid, cod liver, anterior pituitary, blood of animals, stomach tissue"]},{"question":"Name the metallic source used in treatment of iron deficiency anemia.","answers":["Zinc","Mercury","Iodine","Iron"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Iron"]},{"question":"Drugs obtained by altering only the chemical structure but retaining the nucleus are called:","answers":["Semi-synthetic","Herbal","Plant","Synthetic"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Semi-synthetic"]},{"question":"Name the microorganism from which penicillin is obtained.","answers":["Streptomycin","Aminoglycosides","Penicillium notatum","Actinobacteria"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Penicillium notatum"]},{"question":"Recombinant DNA technology involves:","answers":["alteration of only chemical structure","retaining nucleus from natural source","partial herbal and chemical synthesis","cleavage of DNA by enzyme restriction endonucleases and insertion into bacterial cultures"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["cleavage of DNA by enzyme restriction endonucleases and insertion into bacterial cultures"]},{"question":"List the advantages of recombinant DNA technology.","answers":["produces crude drugs, impure form, highly antigenic","easy technique, no special requirements, low cost","requires well equipped lab, highly trained staff, complex process","Huge drug production, drug in pure form, less antigenic"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Huge drug production, drug in pure form, less antigenic"]},{"question":"Name the drug classes for pain and consciousness.","answers":["antibiotics, antifungals, antimalarials","NSAIDs, opioids, local anesthetics","antihypertensives, diuretics, statins","bronchodilators, corticosteroids, leukotriene antagonists"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["NSAIDs, opioids, local anesthetics"]},{"question":"Name the classification of ADR based on causation.","answers":["local and systemic","Type A and Type B","idiosyncratic and augmented pharmacology","mild and severe"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Type A and Type B"]},{"question":"Type A reactions are:","answers":["dose dependent and predictable, constitute 80% of ADRs","dose independent but predictable","constitute 20% of ADRs, non predictable","idiosyncratic, non dose related"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["dose dependent and predictable, constitute 80% of ADRs"]},{"question":"Name the drug classes for cardiovascular system.","answers":["analgesics, anesthetics, antidepressants","Beta-blockers, calcium channel blockers, diuretics, ACE inhibitors, statins, antiarrhythmics, antianginals, anticoagulants","antihistamines, bronchodilators, corticosteroids","antibiotics, antifungals, antimalarials"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Beta-blockers, calcium channel blockers, diuretics, ACE inhibitors, statins, antiarrhythmics, antianginals, anticoagulants"]},{"question":"Drugs administered through mouth are called:","answers":["Enteral route","Topical route","Parenteral route","Inhalation route"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Enteral route"]},{"question":"Drugs administered into blood are called:","answers":["Enteral route","Topical route","Inhalation route","Parenteral route"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Parenteral route"]},{"question":"Name the classification of ADR based on severity as per FDA.","answers":["mild, moderate, severe","local, systemic","Death, life-threatening, hospitalization, disability, congenital anomaly, intervention to prevent impairment","dose dependent, dose independent"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Death, life-threatening, hospitalization, disability, congenital anomaly, intervention to prevent impairment"]},{"question":"Drugs most commonly abused include:","answers":["Alcohol, amphetamines, barbiturates, benzodiazepines, cocaine, opioids","NSAIDs, proton pump inhibitors, H2 blockers","Antihypertensives, statins, diuretics","Antibiotics, antimalarials, antifungals"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Alcohol, amphetamines, barbiturates, benzodiazepines, cocaine, opioids"]},{"question":"Name the gastrointestinal drug classes for lower digestive tract.","answers":["Antacids, reflux suppressants, antiflatulents","Proton pump inhibitors, H2 blockers, cytoprotectants","Laxatives, antispasmodics, antidiarrheals, bile acid sequestrants, opioids","Prostaglandin analogues, mucosal protectants"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Laxatives, antispasmodics, antidiarrheals, bile acid sequestrants, opioids"]},{"question":"Drugs affecting CNS include:","answers":["NSAIDs, antibiotics, antimalarials","Bronchodilators, antihistamines, leukotriene antagonists","Beta blockers, calcium channel blockers, ACE inhibitors","Psychedelics, hypnotics, anaesthetics, antipsychotics, antidepressants, anticonvulsants, anxiolytics, stimulants, benzodiazepines, dopamine antagonists, anticholinergics"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Psychedelics, hypnotics, anaesthetics, antipsychotics, antidepressants, anticonvulsants, anxiolytics, stimulants, benzodiazepines, dopamine antagonists, anticholinergics"]},{"question":"Name the mechanisms of ADRs:","answers":["Comorbid disease states, dose dependency","Abnormal pharmacokinetics, synergistic effects between drug-disease or two drugs","Augmented pharmacology, type B reactions","Idiosyncratic reactions, genetic factors"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Abnormal pharmacokinetics, synergistic effects between drug-disease or two drugs"]},{"question":"Drugs obtained from plants include:","answers":["Bacteria, fungi, viruses","Leaves, flowers, fruits, seeds, roots, bark, stem","Whole plant, plant extracts","Organs, glands, tissues"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Leaves, flowers, fruits, seeds, roots, bark, stem"]},{"question":"Name the sources of drugs from Earth:","answers":["Plants, animals","Microbes","Metallic and non-metallic minerals","Synthetic chemicals"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Metallic and non-metallic minerals"]},{"question":"Name the classes of antibiotics:","answers":["Corticosteroids, inhaled bronchodilators","Penicillins, cephalosporins, aminoglycosides, fluoroquinolones, macrolides, tetracyclines, sulfonamides","Antimalarials, antifungals, antivirals","NSAIDs, proton pump inhibitors"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Penicillins, cephalosporins, aminoglycosides, fluoroquinolones, macrolides, tetracyclines, sulfonamides"]},{"question":"Drugs derived from animal sources include:","answers":["Organs, tissues","Hormones, enzymes, blood products","Microbes","Whole animals, animal extracts"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Hormones, enzymes, blood products"]},{"question":"Name the antihypertensive drug classes:","answers":["NSAIDs, nitrates","ACE inhibitors, ARBs, beta blockers, calcium channel blockers, thiazide diuretics","Antipsychotics, antidepressants","Alpha blockers, loop diuretics"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["ACE inhibitors, ARBs, beta blockers, calcium channel blockers, thiazide diuretics"]},{"question":"Drugs obtained by chemical synthesis include:","answers":["Modified microbial products","Herbal/plant extracts","Those with new chemical entities not found in nature","Semi-synthetic drugs"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Those with new chemical entities not found in nature"]},{"question":"Name the classification of drugs based on origin:","answers":["Natural, semi-synthetic, synthetic, animal, microbial, biotechnology","Plant, mineral, synthetic, recombinant","Herbal, chemical, animal, earth","Whole organisms, extracts, fractions"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Natural, semi-synthetic, synthetic, animal, microbial, biotechnology"]},{"question":"Drugs administered intranasally include:","answers":["Topical emollients, creams","Inhaled bronchodilators, steroids","Decongestants, antiallergics, corticosteroids","Oral analgesics, antibiotics"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Decongestants, antiallergics, corticosteroids"]},{"question":"What is the body's response to stress?","answers":["Parasympathetic nervous system activation","Neural communication dysfunction","Hormone secretion","Sympathetic nervous system activation"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Sympathetic nervous system activation"]},{"question":"Which structure in the brain is responsible for the fight-or-flight response?","answers":["Prefrontal cortex","Hippocampus","Hypothalamus","Amygdala"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Hypothalamus"]},{"question":"What is the role of the amygdala in stress response?","answers":["Synthesizing neurotransmitters","Memory formation","Modulating stress response mechanisms","Regulating cognitive processes"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Modulating stress response mechanisms"]},{"question":"Which brain structure plays an important role in memory formation and can be damaged by chronic stress?","answers":["Prefrontal cortex","Hypothalamus","Amygdala","Hippocampus"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Hippocampus"]},{"question":"What is the function of the prefrontal cortex?","answers":["Synthesizing stress hormones","Stimulating the pituitary gland","Modulating mood","Regulating cognitive processes"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Regulating cognitive processes"]},{"question":"Which area in the brain is the principal site of the synthesis of norepinephrine?","answers":["Raphe nucleus","Prefrontal cortex","Hypothalamus","Locus coeruleus"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Locus coeruleus"]},{"question":"Which hormone is released by the pituitary gland during a stress response?","answers":["Serotonin","Norepinephrine","Corticotropin-releasing hormone","Adrenocorticotropic hormone"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Adrenocorticotropic hormone"]},{"question":"Where is cortisol synthesized in the body?","answers":["Adrenal cortex","Hypothalamus","Amygdala","Raphe nucleus"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Adrenal cortex"]},{"question":"What is the primary function of cortisol during a stress response?","answers":["Redistribute energy (glucose) to regions of the body that need it most","Suppress the immune system","Modulate mood and anxiety","Improve memory formation"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Redistribute energy (glucose) to regions of the body that need it most"]},{"question":"Which neurotransmitter is released by the central nervous system's sympathetic branch in the fight-or-flight response to stress?","answers":["Norepinephrine","Neuropeptide Y","Cortisol","Serotonin"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Norepinephrine"]},{"question":"Which neurotransmitter is synthesized in the raphe nucleus and plays an important role in mood regulation?","answers":["Serotonin","Corticotropin-releasing hormone","Adrenocorticotropic hormone","Norepinephrine"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Serotonin"]},{"question":"What is the function of neuropeptide Y in the brain?","answers":["Regulate cognitive processes","Modulate pain sensation","Play a role in anxiety and stress resiliency","Synthesize stress hormones"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Play a role in anxiety and stress resiliency"]},{"question":"Which chemical messenger is responsible for mood modification and acts as a coping strategy?","answers":["Mood modification","Adrenocorticotropic hormone","Norepinephrine","Cortisol"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Mood modification"]},{"question":"What is the pituitary gland responsible for?","answers":["Regulating cognitive processes","Synthesizing stress hormones","Modulating mood","Releasing various hormones that regulate homeostasis"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Releasing various hormones that regulate homeostasis"]},{"question":"Which organ of the endocrine system is chiefly responsible for the synthesis of stress hormones?","answers":["Pituitary gland","Pancreas","Thyroid gland","Adrenal gland"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Adrenal gland"]},{"question":"Which hormone is released by the pituitary gland to stimulate the adrenal gland?","answers":["Norepinephrine","Adrenocorticotropic hormone","Serotonin","Cortisol"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Adrenocorticotropic hormone"]},{"question":"What is the main function of cortisol?","answers":["Improve memory formation","Redistribute energy (glucose) to regions of the body that need it most","Modulate mood and anxiety","Suppress the immune system"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Redistribute energy (glucose) to regions of the body that need it most"]},{"question":"Which neurotransmitter is released by the locus coeruleus during a stress response in the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":["Serotonin","Cortisol","Norepinephrine","Neuropeptide Y"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Norepinephrine"]},{"question":"What is the role of serotonin in the brain?","answers":["Regulate appetite and feeding behavior","Modulate pain sensation","Synthesize stress hormones","Play an important role in mood regulation"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Play an important role in mood regulation"]},{"question":"Which neurotransmitter is synthesized in the raphe nucleus and plays a role in mood regulation?","answers":["Norepinephrine","Corticotropin-releasing hormone","Adrenocorticotropic hormone","Serotonin"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Serotonin"]},{"question":"What is the function of neuropeptide Y in the brain?","answers":["Modulate pain sensation","Regulate cognitive processes","Synthesize stress hormones","Play a role in anxiety and stress resiliency"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Play a role in anxiety and stress resiliency"]},{"question":"Which chemical messenger is responsible for mood modification and acts as a coping strategy?","answers":["Mood modification","Cortisol","Adrenocorticotropic hormone","Norepinephrine"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Mood modification"]},{"question":"What is the pituitary gland responsible for?","answers":["Regulating cognitive processes","Releasing various hormones that regulate homeostasis","Modulating mood","Synthesizing stress hormones"],"correct_answer_indices":[1],"correct_answers":["Releasing various hormones that regulate homeostasis"]},{"question":"Which organ of the endocrine system is chiefly responsible for the synthesis of stress hormones?","answers":["Pituitary gland","Pancreas","Adrenal gland","Thyroid gland"],"correct_answer_indices":[2],"correct_answers":["Adrenal gland"]},{"question":"Which hormone is released by the pituitary gland to stimulate the adrenal gland?","answers":["Cortisol","Serotonin","Norepinephrine","Adrenocorticotropic hormone"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Adrenocorticotropic hormone"]},{"question":"What is the main function of cortisol?","answers":["Redistribute energy (glucose) to regions of the body that need it most","Suppress the immune system","Improve memory formation","Modulate mood and anxiety"],"correct_answer_indices":[0],"correct_answers":["Redistribute energy (glucose) to regions of the body that need it most"]},{"question":"Which neurotransmitter is released by the locus coeruleus during a stress response in the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":["Serotonin","Neuropeptide Y","Cortisol","Norepinephrine"],"correct_answer_indices":[3],"correct_answers":["Norepinephrine"]}]